Register of the Green Bay (Wis.). Fire Dept.: Log Books and Fire Record Books, 1899-1993
Wisconsin Historical Society
Green Bay (Wis.). Fire Dept.: Log Books and Fire Record Books, 1899-1993
Green Bay (Wis.). Fire Dept.
Brown Series 176
52 reels of microfilm (35 mm)
Housed at the University of Wisconsin-Green Bay Archives and Area Research Center; owned by the Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Record of fire department engine runs consisting of log books, 1899-1927, 1954-1993; fire record books, 1923-1954; and maps of Green Bay's west side, circa 1980.
Available only on microfilm.
The records are divided into four series: LOG BOOKS, MISCELLANEOUS LOG BOOKS, FIRE RECORDS and MAPS. The volume numbers were assigned by WHS as a convenient way to facilitate microfilming and do not imply any order. The Fire Books are more informative for documenting the day-to-day activities of the Fire Department than the Log Books.
The LOG BOOKS are in two chronological sequences: 1899-1927 and 1954-1993. From 1967-1976 there are separate books for fire station #1 and fire station #2. MISCELLANEOUS LOG BOOKS are those that do not fit into either of these sequences and arranged by the date of the first entry. The LOG BOOKS from 1899-1927 contain a daily record of the duty roster and the cost of meals. Some fire calls and other notations (usually concerning equipment) are listed within the rosters and include the time the fire truck left and returned and the location of the fire. By the time of the 1954-1993 sequence of books, the information about meals was dropped and more details of the fire calls were added. Also the volumes appear to be more of dispatcher's log books for squad calls rather than fire station records. The gap in log books, 1928-1953 is covered by the FIRE RECORDS, which contain more substantial information than the log books.
FIRE RECORDS, 1928-1953, typically contain the date of the fire call, alarm (phone or box), location, time, names of building's owners and occupants, type of building, cause, equipment used, value of the structure and contents, and remarks. Later records are more detailed about types of equipment used and include first aid administered.
The MAPS of Green Bay may have been created in 1939 and revised periodically through 1980. The volume consists of several maps, each showing an area of the city. Notations indicate all main valves, tapping sleeves and valves, reducers, hydrants and hydrant valves, and size of hydrant valves. The maps also indicate building locations and railroads.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Larry Erdmann via the Neville Museum, 1999. C1999/017
Contents List
- Log books, 1899-1927, 1954-1971, Brown Series 176
  - 1899 August 4-1900 May 24 (Volume 1, Othertype 1/1)
  - 1901 April 2-1902 April 2 (Volume 2, Othertype 1/2)
  - 1902 April 3-1903 February 8 (Volume 3, Othertype 1/3)
  - 1903 February 9-1904 June 2 (Volume 5, Othertype 2/1)
  - 1904 June 3-1905 March 2 (Volume 8, Othertype 2/4)
  - 1905 March 28-1906 January 15 (Volume 9, Othertype 3/1)
  - 1906 January 16-1906 November 3 (Volume 10, Othertype 3/2)
  - 1906 November 4-1907 August 28 (Volume 11, Othertype 3/3)
  - 1907 August 29-1908 September 30 (Volume 12, Othertype 3/4)
  - 1908 October 1-1910 February 12 (Volume 13, Othertype 4/1)
  - 1910 February 15-1911 March 15 (Volume 14, Othertype 4/2)
  - 1915 November 9-1916 December 11 (Volume 15, Othertype 4/3)
  - 1919 October 5-1920 July 31 (Volume 16, Othertype 5/1)
  - 1920 August 1-1921 December 13 (Volume 17, Othertype 5/2)
  - 1921 December 14-1923 April 27 (Volume 18, Othertype 5/3)
  - 1921 December 14-1923 April 27 (Volume 20, Othertype 6/2)
  - 1924 September 9-1925 July 5 (Volume 22, Othertype 7/1)
  - 1925 July 6-1926 May 1 (Volume 23, Othertype 7/2)
  - 1927 February 2-1927 December 16 (Volume 25, Othertype 7/4)
  - 1954 August 24-1956 April 30 (Volume 37, Othertype 10/1)
  - 1956 May 1-1957 August 31 (Volume 40, Othertype 11/2)
  - 1957 September 1-1958 December 31 (Volume 43, Othertype 13/1)
  - 1959 January 1-1959 October 18 (Volume 45, Othertype 14/1)
  - 1959 October 19-1960 July 26 (Volume 47, Othertype 15/1)
  - 1960 July 27-1961 April 25 (Volume 49, Othertype 16/1)
  - 1964 April 6-1964 December 31 (Volume 53, Othertype 18/1)
  - 1965 January 1-1965 September 2 (Volume 55, Othertype 19/1)
  - 1965 September 3-1966 May 2 (Volume 56, Othertype 19/2)
  - 1966 May 3-1966 December 18 (Volume 57, Othertype 20/1)
  - 1966 December 19-1967 August 28 (Volume 58, Othertype 20/2)
  - 1967 August 28-1968 April 24 (Volume 60, Othertype 21/2)
  - 1968 April 24-1968 December 21 (Volume 62, Othertype 22/2)
  - 1968 December 21-1969 August 22 (Volume 63, Othertype 23/1)
  - 1969 August 22-1970 April 1 (Volume 65, Othertype 24/1)
  - 1970 April 1-1970 October 31 (Volume 66, Othertype 24/2)
  - 1970 November 1-1971 June 1 (Volume 67, Othertype 25/1)
  - Fire Station #1
    - 1971 June 1-1971 December 25 (Volume 69, Othertype 26/1)
    - 1971 December 25-1972 July 9 (Volume 70, Othertype 26/2)
    - 1972 July 10-1972 December 31 (Volume 72, Othertype 27/2)
    - 1973 January 1-1973 July 6 (Volume 73, Othertype 28/1)
    - 1973 July 6-1974 January 16 (Volume 75, Othertype 29/1)
    - 1974 January 16-1974 August 7 (Volume 76, Othertype 29/2)
    - 1974 August 8-1975 March 2 (Volume 78, Othertype 30/2)
    - 1975 March 2-1975 August 29 (Volume 79, Othertype 31/1)
    - 1975 August 29-1976 March 10 (Volume 81, Othertype 32/1)
    - 1976 March 11-1976 September 27 (Volume 82, Othertype 32/2)
    - 1976 September 27-1977 April 21 (Volume 83, Othertype 33/1)
    - 1977 April 21-1977 November 15 (Volume 84, Othertype 33/2)
    - 1977 November 15-1978 June 1 (Volume 85, Othertype 34/1)
    - 1978 June 1-1978 December 21 (Volume 86, Othertype 34/2)
    - 1978 December 22-1979 July 10 (Volume 87, Othertype 35/1)
    - 1979 July 10-1980 January 17 (Volume 88, Othertype 35/2)
    - 1980 January 17-1980 July 20 (Volume 89, Othertype 36/1)
    - 1980 July 21-1981 January 29 (Volume 90, Othertype 36/2)
    - 1981 January 29-1981 August 30 (Volume 91, Othertype 37/1)
    - 1981 August 31-1982 April 6 (Volume 92, Othertype 37/2)
    - 1982 April 6-1982 November 1 (Volume 93, Othertype 38/1)
    - 1982 November 1-1983 June 7 (Volume 94, Othertype 38/2)
    - 1983 June 8-1984 January 5 (Volume 95, Othertype 39/1)
    - 1984 January 5-1984 August 17 (Volume 96, Othertype 39/2)
    - 1984 August 17-1985 April 6 (Volume 97, Othertype 40/1)
    - 1985 April 6-1985 November 16 (Volume 98, Othertype 40/2)
    - 1985 November 17-1986 June 23 (Volume 99, Othertype 41/1)
    - 1986 June 24-1987 January 24 (Volume 100, Othertype 41/2)
    - 1987 January 29-1987 August 28 (Volume 101, Othertype 42/1)
    - 1987 August 29-1988 March 28 (Volume 102, Othertype 42/2)
    - 1988 March 29-1988 October 25 (Volume 104, Othertype 43/2)
    - 1988 October 25-1989 July 1 (Volume 105, Othertype 44/1)
    - 1989 July 1-1990 March 15 (Volume 106, Othertype 44/2)
    - 1990 March 15-1990 November 13 (Volume 111, Othertype 47/1)
    - 1990 November 14-1991 August 1 (Volume 113, Othertype 48/1)
    - 1991 August 21-1992 April 29 (Volume 116, Othertype 49/2)
    - 1992 April 30-1993 January 4 (Volume 118, Othertype 50/2)
  - Fire Station #2
    - 1967 January 1-1968 April 20 (Volume 59, Othertype 21/1)
    - 1968 April 21-1969 August 15 (Volume 61, Othertype 22/1)
    - 1969 August 15-1970 October 31 (Volume 64, Othertype 23/2)
    - 1970 November 1-1972 January 28 (Volume 68, Othertype 23/2)
    - 1972 January 29-1973 April 23 (Volume 71, Othertype 27/1)
    - 1973 April 24-1974 April 28 (Volume 74, Othertype 28/2)
    - 1974 April 29-1975 April 22 (Volume 77, Othertype 30/1)
    - 1975 April 24-1976 April 12 (Volume 80, Othertype 31/2)
- Miscellaneous log books, 1902-1993
  - 1902 July 1-1903 December 17 (Volume 4, Othertype 1/4)
  - 1903 September 30-1904 October 18 (Volume 6, Othertype 2/2)
    #3 Hose company
  - 1903 December 14-1904 December 31 (Volume 7, Othertype 2/3)
  - 1923 September 23-1926 June 14 (Volume 21, Othertype 6/3)
  - 1926 June 15-1927 September 12 (Volume 24, Othertype 7/3)
  - 1954 January 1-1963 January 7 (Volume 123, Othertype 51/4)
    #92 pump report
  - 1954 August 2-1955 February 5 (Volume 124, Othertype 51/5)
    squad report
  - 1956 January 1-1965 October 1 (Volume 125, Othertype 51/6)
  - 1962 January 19-1962 October 9 (Volume 51, Othertype 17/1)
    pump #1 report
  - 1964 November 1-1964 December 31 (Volume 126, Othertype 51/7)
    pump #92 report
  - 1988 January 4-1992 September 9 (Volume 103, Othertype 43/1)
  - 1989 January 1-1990 March 24 (Volume 107, Othertype 45/1)
  - 1990 January 1-1993 April 21 (Volume 108, Othertype 45/2)
  - 1990 February 26-1991 May 24 (Volume 109, Othertype 46/1)
  - 1990 August 25-1991 April 21 (Volume 112, Othertype 47/2)
  - 1991 April 22-1992 June 23 (Volume 114, Othertype 48/2)
  - 1991 June 24-1992 October 18 (Volume 115, Othertype 49/1)
  - 1991 September 27-1993 April 21 (Volume 117, Othertype 50/1)
  - 1992 June 24-1993 April 21 (Volume 119, Othertype 50/3)
  - 1992 August 6-1993 April 19 (Volume 120, Othertype 51/1)
  - 1992 October 18-1993 April 21 (Volume 121, Othertype 51/2)
  - 1992 December 5-1993 April 20 (Volume 122, Othertype 51/3)
- Fire books, 1923-1954
  - 1923 January-1927 December 31 (Volume 19, Othertype 6/1)
  - 1928 January 1-1931 January 3 (Volume 26, Othertype 8/1)
  - 1931 January 1-1933 December 30 (Volume 27, Othertype 8/2)
  - 1934 January 1-1936 October 30 (Volume 28, Othertype 8/3)
  - 1936 November 1-1938 September 22 (Volume 29, Othertype 8/4)
  - 1941 June 15-1943 December 31 (Volume 30, Othertype 8/5)
  - 1944 January 1-1945 December 31 (Volume 31, Othertype 8/6)
  - 1946 January 1-1947 December 31 (Volume 32, Othertype 9/1)
  - 1948 January 1-1949 October 25 (Volume 33, Othertype 9/2)
  - 1949 October 26-1951 June 1 (Volume 34, Othertype 9/3)
  - 1951 June 1-1952 October 31 (Volume 35, Othertype 9/4)
  - 1952 November 1-1954 April 13 (Volume 36, Othertype 9/5)
- Maps of Green Bay (Reel 52)